<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An epistle for the most pure amity and unity in the spirit and life of God to all sincere-hearted-souls ... that desire that God's truth and righteousnes in power, may be exalted over all within them and without them (in the whole earth) for ever / by your friend in the purest love, John Perrot.</title>
            <author>J. P. (John Perrot), d. 1671?</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 32 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A54429</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">13178234</idno>
  <idno type="VID">98357</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240867055</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing P1616</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R3018</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">13178234</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A54429)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 98357)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 433:12)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An epistle for the most pure amity and unity in the spirit and life of God to all sincere-hearted-souls ... that desire that God's truth and righteousnes in power, may be exalted over all within them and without them (in the whole earth) for ever / by your friend in the purest love, John Perrot.</title>
                  <author>J. P. (John Perrot), d. 1671?</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>16 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Robert Wilson,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1662]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Date of publication from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Friends' Library, London.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Concord --  Religious aspects --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>John Latta </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:98357:1"/>
            <p>AN EPISTLE For the most PURE Amity and Unity IN The SPIRIT and LIFE of GOD: To all SINCERE-HEARTED-SOULS, Whether Called,
<list>
                  <item>PRESBYTERIANS,</item>
                  <item>INDEPENDENTS,</item>
                  <item>BAPTISTS,</item>
                  <item>SEEKERS,</item>
                  <item>QUAKERS, or Others,</item>
               </list> Under any other <hi>Denomination</hi> whatsoever, that de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sire that God's TRUTH and RIGHTEOUS<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>NES in <hi>Power,</hi> may be EXALTED over all, <hi>within</hi> them and <hi>without</hi> them (in the whole Earth) for Ever.</p>
            <p>By your FRIEND in the PUREST LOVE, <hi>JOHN PERROT.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>Robert Wilson.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb facs="tcp:98357:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:98357:2"/>
            <head>
               <hi>AN EPISTLE For</hi> The most Pure <hi>AMITY</hi> and <hi>UNITY</hi> in the Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit and Life of God, to all sincere hearted Soules; whether called <hi>Presbiterians, Independents, Baptists, Qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kers,</hi> &amp;c.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>DEAR FRIENDS,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>VVIthout <hi>respect</hi> to any of your <hi>Persons,</hi> but for the <hi>Seed's sake</hi> of GOD in all <hi>your Souls</hi> (in the Fathers Love) I <hi>Salute</hi> and <hi>Greet</hi> you, as one that is in <hi>Spiritual Labour</hi> and <hi>Travel,</hi> often compassed with <hi>Pangs,</hi> and frequently girded with <hi>sore Throwes,</hi> in the Exercise of <hi>Sighings,</hi> with bowels <hi>melting</hi> and <hi>bleeding</hi> until <hi>Israel</hi> be gathered as <hi>One,</hi> to feed as a hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venly <hi>Flock,</hi> of the <hi>Shepherd's Love</hi> in the freshest, and greenest <hi>Pastures</hi> of his own <hi>Delights</hi> and <hi>Pleasures.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Ah! when I <hi>consider</hi> of the <hi>dispersed</hi> and <hi>scattered condition</hi> and <hi>state</hi> of the <hi>People</hi> principally <hi>professing God</hi> and <hi>Godliness,</hi> not having <hi>Unity</hi> in their hearts, with the <hi>profane</hi> of the Land, and how they are <hi>divers</hi> in Judge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments and Points of <hi>Opinion,</hi> and in <hi>this day</hi> and <hi>hour,</hi> like so many <hi>poor Sheep</hi> (in a stormy season) in a <hi>Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derness</hi> and <hi>Desart,</hi> some feeding on the <hi>Mountains</hi> of
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:98357:3"/> the desolate Places, others on the <hi>little Hills,</hi> others among the <hi>thickets,</hi> and <hi>prickie Bryars</hi> and <hi>Thornes;</hi> others in the <hi>Plaines,</hi> and others in <hi>Valleyes</hi> thereof; and yet but <hi>all</hi> belonging unto <hi>one Sheepheard,</hi> being of <hi>one heart,</hi> and only <hi>one desire</hi> to <hi>God-wards,</hi> which <hi>God</hi> alone hath <hi>begotten</hi> (in all) of his own <hi>free Grace</hi> and <hi>Mercy;</hi> only there stands some certain <hi>Hedges</hi> of <hi>Opinions,</hi> which have divided between <hi>Sheep</hi> and <hi>Sheep</hi> of the <hi>Shepherd,</hi> and between <hi>true Desirers,</hi> and <hi>true Desirers after the God of Jacob,</hi> and <hi>Saviour of Israel:</hi> Oh! when I have <hi>considered</hi> the slender <hi>Causes,</hi> and yet the vast <hi>Severations</hi> of such <hi>Peoples</hi> occasioned thereby, I can say, <hi>Mourning</hi> hath attended me as an <hi>Hand-maid,</hi> and <hi>Grief</hi> hath covered me as <hi>a Garment;</hi> and then have I said in my Soul, how shall the <hi>Uniting of all this holy Seed be,</hi> for us <hi>all</hi> to dwell as <hi>in one house,</hi> as the <hi>Family</hi> of <hi>one Father,</hi> as the <hi>Children</hi> of <hi>one God,</hi> yea, as the <hi>living pure Members</hi> of <hi>one Body;</hi> as for me, I am <hi>a Worme,</hi> and <hi>one</hi> of the <hi>weakest</hi> of <hi>Wormes,</hi> and <hi>creeping Things</hi> before the Lord, and one but in whom a Ray of his <hi>appearance</hi> is risen and sprung up, which hath begotten in me a breathing <hi>desire</hi> after <hi>God,</hi> as is the like in the <hi>rest</hi> of the Souls, which my heavenly Father hath <hi>created,</hi> who walk under <hi>another Denomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation</hi> in respect of his <hi>true Worship;</hi> and I knew not <hi>this God,</hi> nay nor ever could know <hi>him,</hi> but by and of his own <hi>meer Mercy</hi> and <hi>free Love</hi> and <hi>Grace,</hi> of his <hi>E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verlasting Life;</hi> and being <hi>first</hi> unable to bring <hi>my Soul</hi> where I am <hi>brought,</hi> and now being altogether as <hi>un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able</hi> to <hi>keep</hi> and <hi>preserve my Soul</hi> where I am <hi>kept,</hi> am also as <hi>unable</hi> to bring all the <hi>Scattered</hi> in my <hi>bosom,</hi> and bear all the <hi>Dispersed</hi> in my <hi>breast</hi> and <hi>armes,</hi> unto
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:98357:3"/> the <hi>rest</hi> where my God hath brought me, though <hi>great</hi> is <hi>my love;</hi> Ah! my Love, my unspeakable <hi>Love</hi> to you <hi>all,</hi> in which I can cry <hi>Father, how long, how long</hi> shall the <hi>Day be,</hi> until all shall be united in one, even in thy own eternal Spirit of <hi>holynesse</hi> and <hi>blessednesse</hi> (for which there is a cry in the Earth, The Beasts travel in pain, and the Wormes and Birds are pained in sorrow, until <hi>Redemption</hi> cometh, and the <hi>Restoration</hi> appears in the Land.) Since the <hi>Travel</hi> is for <hi>thy glory,</hi> and the <hi>end</hi> of the <hi>Labours</hi> for <hi>thy praise,</hi> that thou mayest be for ever <hi>known</hi> to be <hi>King</hi> of <hi>Saints</hi> to the ends of the Earth, and <hi>all Kingdoms</hi> become <hi>thine</hi> alone <hi>Empire,</hi> that <hi>thy renown may</hi> be over <hi>all</hi> for ever?</p>
            <p>Well, when I have <hi>considered how,</hi> which <hi>way,</hi> by <hi>whom,</hi> and <hi>when</hi> shall the <hi>Work</hi> be wrought (which I travel in hope for, and walk bowed down until it comes to pass, yet often refreshed as with new Wine in the feeling of the faith, that it shall surely come to pass) I could say, <hi>Counsel</hi> is with the <hi>Mighty,</hi> and he that is <hi>diligent</hi> in <hi>waiting</hi> shall <hi>see</hi> the <hi>glorious Way</hi> of his work<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, which now appears to me is coming to pass, e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven <hi>that</hi> which shall perfect <hi>his praise:</hi> And therefore, among the <hi>many Flocks</hi> of the <hi>one Shephard</hi> (which are yet severed by the partition Walls of Opinions) the Lord hath suffered the <hi>Dragon</hi> to <hi>awake</hi> and <hi>rouze</hi> the <hi>Lyon,</hi> and the <hi>Wolf</hi> to <hi>yell</hi> for the <hi>Beare,</hi> and <hi>they</hi> have <hi>entered</hi> the <hi>Desarts with Roarings,</hi> and their <hi>Noises</hi> are <hi>dreadful</hi> and <hi>terrible;</hi> and <hi>their runnings to</hi> and <hi>fro,</hi> and <hi>huntings up</hi> and <hi>down,</hi> What are they for? to <hi>scatter</hi> from the compleat <hi>Number,</hi> to <hi>rend,</hi> to <hi>tear,</hi> and <hi>divide</hi> Feet <hi>from</hi> Body, and <hi>Bowels</hi> from <hi>Belly, Vitals</hi> from <hi>Breast,</hi> and <hi>Hands</hi> and <hi>Armes</hi> from <hi>Shoulders,</hi> yea,
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:98357:4"/> the <hi>compleat Body</hi> from the <hi>perfect Head:</hi> And seeing, this is the <hi>Nature</hi> of the <hi>Beasts.</hi> What then is the <hi>nature</hi> of the <hi>Sheep?</hi> As fast as the <hi>Beasts of Prey</hi> do <hi>drive, hunt</hi> and <hi>pursue,</hi> even <hi>so swiftly</hi> to fly <hi>flocking together;</hi> not as <hi>many,</hi> but singly, <hi>as one Body</hi> in the <hi>Unity, Love, Life, Peace, Joy, Protection</hi> and <hi>Everlasting-Power</hi> of the <hi>one Shepherd, Jesus,</hi> the for-ever <hi>blessed King</hi> of the <hi>Israel</hi> of the <hi>holy God,</hi> in whom is <hi>our Salvation, safety</hi> and certain <hi>preservation. Down, Down</hi> therefore, with the <hi>Walls</hi> and <hi>Hedges</hi> of <hi>Division,</hi> and <hi>draw quickly</hi> into the holy <hi>Spirit</hi> of <hi>conjunction;</hi> for may I not say? We serve not an <hi>Opinion,</hi> but the <hi>God of Wisdom,</hi> of whom our Understandings are <hi>given us,</hi> and if we <hi>see not</hi> by anothers <hi>Spectacles,</hi> yet if <hi>we see</hi> with the <hi>Eye that God hath given us,</hi> do we not <hi>see well</hi> until he makes us <hi>see better?</hi> yea, if we <hi>discern</hi> men walking like <hi>Trees,</hi> shall we not all be <hi>content,</hi> until we <hi>see</hi> men walking <hi>as men?</hi> For surely the <hi>least</hi> that we see of <hi>God,</hi> is what is <hi>given us of God,</hi> and not what of <hi>our selves,</hi> we could acquire <hi>to ourselves;</hi> and therefore let him that hath <hi>most,</hi> be <hi>patient,</hi> and <hi>wait</hi> in <hi>watching</hi> and <hi>praying,</hi> until he that hath <hi>the least Mite,</hi> be <hi>possessed</hi> of as great a <hi>Treasure</hi> as himself; and let not <hi>him</hi> that hath <hi>Riches,</hi> exclude a <hi>begging Orphant</hi> out of his Habitation; for that is not <hi>as God</hi> (whose Image of <hi>Love</hi> and <hi>Mercie</hi> we are to bear) hath <hi>done</hi> by any <hi>of us</hi> that have <hi>experience</hi> of his <hi>goodnesse;</hi> and let not him that hath but a <hi>Penny,</hi> murmur against him that is endowed with a 1000 <hi>Pounds,</hi> for it is <hi>God</hi> that hath <hi>gifted</hi> you <hi>both</hi> of his <hi>own Grace</hi> and <hi>Mercy;</hi> wherefore let your <hi>Joy</hi> be <hi>in God,</hi> and your <hi>Thanks-giving</hi> be <hi>unto God,</hi> for the <hi>gift</hi> that you have <hi>received</hi> from him; and let the <hi>greatest en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riched</hi>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:98357:4"/> (in his Gift) pray God that the <hi>least enriched</hi> may be <hi>content</hi> with <hi>his Portion</hi> until <hi>more</hi> be <hi>given;</hi> and let the <hi>least enriched</hi> (in his measure of the Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sure) <hi>pray</hi> and <hi>supplicate</hi> the <hi>Father,</hi> that with the <hi>Riches</hi> and <hi>abundance</hi> of the <hi>pretious Things,</hi> by no means the <hi>greatest endowed</hi> may ever be <hi>puffed up</hi> in heart, but be kept of a <hi>humble</hi> and <hi>low mind</hi> in the Grace, to <hi>glorifie</hi> God in Righteousness to the <hi>end;</hi> and in <hi>this Love,</hi> and <hi>holy Care</hi> and <hi>Tenderness,</hi> all shall <hi>dwell</hi> as in the <hi>sweetest Harmony</hi> of <hi>Heaven,</hi> a <hi>praise</hi> to the <hi>GOD</hi> of <hi>Goodness, Mercy</hi> and <hi>Righteousnesse,</hi> for evermore, Amen.</p>
            <p>Surely, <hi>Dear Friends,</hi> I cannot but again <hi>renewedly</hi> say it, <hi>This</hi> even <hi>this</hi> is the <hi>Day</hi> of <hi>driving</hi> by the <hi>Beasts of Prey;</hi> and therefore may it well be to us all, <hi>the day of flocking</hi> in <hi>one</hi> to the <hi>Fold of the Lamb;</hi> Oh! Consi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, consider, might not the Lord say to us, I called you by the <hi>allurements</hi> of <hi>my Love,</hi> but ye would not <hi>run</hi> at <hi>my Voice;</hi> I have even dealt by you, as with <hi>Enchantments</hi> of harmonious <hi>Sweetnesse,</hi> but you would not be <hi>one,</hi> as I would you should be <hi>one</hi> in me, the God of all your Mercies; and therefore have I <hi>suffered</hi> the <hi>Rod</hi> of the <hi>Wicked,</hi> to smite the <hi>Cheeks</hi> of you <hi>my Children,</hi> that whereto the <hi>Word</hi> did not make you <hi>walk,</hi> the <hi>Rod</hi> may enduce you <hi>to run;</hi> for I am but <hi>one God,</hi> and it is but <hi>one Zeal</hi> of my Name, that is in <hi>you all,</hi> even that which stands in the <hi>meek nature</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainst <hi>Unrighteousness,</hi> the which is perfectly held in the <hi>Love</hi> towards all, whom I have <hi>loved</hi> with the same <hi>Love</hi> that I have <hi>loved you;</hi> for the <hi>love of me,</hi> and of my <hi>appearance</hi> in all (which provokes to holyness) is the savouring <hi>Grace</hi> which <hi>preserves</hi> the <hi>Zeal</hi> of my
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:98357:5"/> House in you, in the liveliest <hi>Knowledge</hi> of me, in which there shall be <hi>no Contention,</hi> but <hi>Content</hi> and <hi>Peace,</hi> and if any <hi>one</hi> be otherwise minded, not reaching into the deeps of my Counsel, wait ye <hi>as one</hi> together (in the <hi>one Love</hi> of <hi>my Life</hi>) and the same shall be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vealed <hi>unto him</hi> also; and here you shall have no <hi>King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom</hi> to <hi>your selves,</hi> no <hi>selfish End,</hi> nor <hi>intrest</hi> of a <hi>Name</hi> or <hi>Fame,</hi> of <hi>High</hi> or <hi>Mighty,</hi> of <hi>Prince</hi> or <hi>Ruler</hi> in my Throne, nor <hi>Masters</hi> over the Heritage, sitting in my Seat of Dignity; but as <hi>one</hi> shall ye be mine, <hi>Servants</hi> to me, and <hi>one</hi> to <hi>another,</hi> and as <hi>one,</hi> will I be <hi>yours,</hi> even from thenceforth everlastingly?</p>
            <p>And now, as this is <hi>the Day</hi> of <hi>driving,</hi> so will the Day manifest what the <hi>driven are;</hi> whether from the <hi>many Flocks,</hi> to the <hi>Kennils</hi> and <hi>Litters</hi> of the <hi>Beast of Prey;</hi> or, the <hi>Flocks</hi> for their own <hi>Intrests</hi> and <hi>Names,</hi> to save and shelter <hi>themselves</hi> in the <hi>thickets of the desarts,</hi> where they have been <hi>feeding;</hi> or, as an <hi>unanimous Number</hi> and <hi>one Flock,</hi> to imbody together in the <hi>pure Spirit</hi> of Life (by which they are called after the name of the Lord's) to be <hi>a praise</hi> to the <hi>Name</hi> of the Lord, who hath suffered <hi>the Day</hi> thus far to come to pass, for the <hi>compleating</hi> of his <hi>Glory</hi> and <hi>Renown,</hi> aimdst the Nations of the Earth.</p>
            <p>To which <hi>three Sorts</hi> I have these <hi>distinct Words</hi> to say, even in the Name and Power of <hi>Jehovah,</hi> the ever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lasting true <hi>Sheepheard</hi> of the true <hi>Israel.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="1">1. <hi>To the Revolters in this day of Driving.</hi> You may have <hi>your time</hi> in the <hi>Den of the Dragon,</hi> and you may <hi>dance</hi> in the <hi>wideness</hi> of <hi>his Jaws,</hi> that are full of <hi>Venom,</hi> against the <hi>Innocent;</hi> but your <hi>Time</hi> is but <hi>short,</hi> to <hi>sport</hi> and <hi>skip</hi> at the sound of <hi>his Organs,</hi> for the Baggs of
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:98357:5"/> the <hi>winde Instruments</hi> will be <hi>broken</hi> with <hi>blowing,</hi> and your <hi>mirth</hi> will be driven <hi>from you</hi> as with a <hi>Whirlewind,</hi> and the <hi>Dragon</hi> that imbowels you in his Womb, will <hi>spue you forth</hi> as a loathsom <hi>Excrement,</hi> so as that you shall be a <hi>hissing</hi> to <hi>Serpents</hi> and <hi>Adders,</hi> and an <hi>abomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation</hi> to <hi>Saints</hi> and <hi>Angels.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="2">2. To the other Sort, <hi>this is the Spirit's Saying,</hi> You that stand <hi>in seperation,</hi> and <hi>seeking</hi> to save <hi>your selves</hi> for <hi>your selves,</hi> and to acquire a <hi>Name</hi> for your proper <hi>Interests;</hi> your <hi>Fleeces</hi> shall be <hi>torn</hi> among <hi>the thickets,</hi> and as a <hi>naked Remnant</hi> shall you come forth in <hi>shame</hi> before <hi>all Eyes,</hi> stripped of the <hi>interests of your Desires,</hi> and shall not be of the <hi>living Number</hi> of my <hi>Heritage,</hi> but by a perfect <hi>Humiliation</hi> in <hi>Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="3">3. <hi>To the third,</hi> that would have nothing <hi>of them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves,</hi> but <hi>GOD</hi> to be <hi>all</hi> in their <hi>Souls,</hi> that <hi>run</hi> and <hi>flock together</hi> (under the Stroakes of the <hi>Rod</hi>) as is <hi>pointed</hi> by the <hi>Spirit</hi> unto them; as they have <hi>waited</hi> for the <hi>day,</hi> so the <hi>day</hi> shall <hi>attend them</hi> with <hi>blessing,</hi> and I will <hi>shorten</hi> the <hi>houres</hi> of <hi>Calamity,</hi> by <hi>rending</hi> the <hi>Renders,</hi> by <hi>tearing to peices</hi> the <hi>Pursuers,</hi> by <hi>preying</hi> on the <hi>Beasts of Prey,</hi> and <hi>devouring</hi> the <hi>Devourers</hi> by the <hi>Breath</hi> of my Mouth, <hi>saith the Lord;</hi> For I will make my <hi>Flock</hi> feed <hi>safely,</hi> and none shall make them afraid, giving them the <hi>longitude</hi> and <hi>latitude</hi> of <hi>Sea,</hi> and <hi>Land</hi> to <hi>inherit</hi> for ever, in the day that <hi>Sheep</hi> shall not <hi>push</hi> against <hi>Sheep,</hi> nor <hi>Lamb</hi> against <hi>Lamb,</hi> but <hi>all</hi> shall <hi>live</hi> in <hi>Love,</hi> as I have chosen them <hi>to love,</hi> and am <hi>the God of their Love,</hi> in whom they shall be <hi>like minded</hi> one <hi>towards</hi> another (as I am <hi>Love</hi> to them <hi>all</hi>) in the indissolvible Covenant of <hi>my Peace, Rest,</hi> and
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:98357:6"/>
               <hi>Joy,</hi> wherein the heavenly and holy <hi>Halelujahs</hi> of my <hi>praise,</hi> shall be <hi>sounded</hi> on the <hi>Harpes</hi> of my glorious <hi>Host,</hi> and they live in the <hi>Pleasures</hi> thereof for ever.</p>
            <p>Ah! I am <hi>overcome</hi> with the <hi>bathings</hi> of the <hi>Oyl</hi> of <hi>these Bottles,</hi> which run <hi>over me</hi> as the <hi>Streams</hi> of <hi>Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers;</hi> and verily, the <hi>Joy</hi> of the Lord <hi>transports</hi> me, that I am even as a <hi>leaking Soul</hi> with <hi>dropings</hi> and <hi>yearn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings,</hi> with <hi>dissolvings,</hi> and <hi>meltings,</hi> before the <hi>Jehovah</hi> of <hi>Glory,</hi> considering his <hi>Glory</hi> (which in himself is too wonderful for me) and as it shall be cast upon <hi>his People,</hi> to the <hi>astonishment</hi> of all the <hi>Sons of Men</hi> upon the <hi>face</hi> of the <hi>Earth,</hi> in the day <hi>of compleating</hi> all the <hi>Mourners</hi> in <hi>Sion,</hi> and <hi>Cryers</hi> in the <hi>Wilderness</hi> (with their Faces towards <hi>Sion,</hi> enquiring the way thither<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards) as <hi>one</hi> in the pure Everlasting <hi>Love</hi> of his <hi>im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mortal Life of Glory,</hi> for which <hi>hour</hi> (though the sence of it, is <hi>ravishing</hi> and <hi>transporting</hi> in the <hi>Life</hi> and <hi>motion</hi> of the <hi>Faith,</hi> which gives <hi>assurance,</hi> that it shall <hi>undoubtedly</hi> come to pass,) yet I <hi>travel</hi> as the <hi>Woman</hi> for the <hi>Birth,</hi> which cannot overcome the <hi>throws,</hi> till the <hi>Birth</hi> is brought <hi>forth</hi> by the Power that hath quickned the Seed in <hi>thousands</hi> and <hi>ten thousands,</hi> to this blessed end of <hi>Life Eternal,</hi> in the <hi>Everlasting Kingdom</hi> of <hi>Peace.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>To which <hi>purpose</hi> I may speak a little, if <hi>speaking</hi> a little could ease me; For the <hi>one Cause</hi> that we are <hi>hurted</hi> and <hi>oppressed</hi> by the <hi>sufferance</hi> of God; and for <hi>another Cause,</hi> that the <hi>Seed of God</hi> in <hi>us all,</hi> is but <hi>one,</hi> of <hi>one Life</hi> and <hi>Nature, begetting Breathings</hi> in us, for <hi>one substance</hi> and <hi>virtue</hi> to satisfie us; and seeing that for the sake of the <hi>Seed</hi> of <hi>God's Love,</hi> we are
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:98357:6"/>
               <hi>persecuted</hi> by the unsatiated <hi>Seed of Enmity;</hi> Why shall there not be a <hi>coherensie</hi> in the Spirit <hi>of Purity?</hi> Seeing it is not <hi>an Opinion</hi> that <hi>unites a Soul</hi> to the <hi>Father</hi> or the <hi>Son,</hi> but the <hi>holy Spirit</hi> which begets <hi>the Soul</hi> into the <hi>sincerity</hi> and <hi>truth</hi> of the <hi>Life</hi> of the <hi>Father</hi> and the <hi>Son,</hi> in which the living <hi>Unity</hi> consists.</p>
            <p>Now this we know, our <hi>end</hi> and <hi>ayme</hi> is the advance<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of the <hi>Glory of God</hi> in the <hi>whole Earth,</hi> as well as in our <hi>own particular Souls,</hi> through the revelation of God's <hi>Righteousness</hi> in <hi>our Souls;</hi> which in how much we have been short of, by so much the cry was great in our inward parts, and I know every individial can <hi>wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness</hi> and <hi>experience</hi> the same unto <hi>this day,</hi> because of the <hi>Mountains of Corruption oppressing,</hi> and the <hi>grindings of transgression</hi> exceedingly <hi>crushing</hi> and <hi>squeezing</hi> the <hi>Souls,</hi> as <hi>clusters</hi> in a <hi>Winepress,</hi> which therefore cannot have <hi>rest</hi> in the pure <hi>Mansions</hi> of <hi>peace</hi> and <hi>satisfaction;</hi> yet I say, as the <hi>desire</hi> is <hi>kindled</hi> after the <hi>holy One,</hi> by the <hi>breathings</hi> of <hi>his Life</hi> in your Souls; <hi>first,</hi> as your Souls are the <hi>created subjects</hi> of God; and <hi>secondly,</hi> as there is a <hi>Seed</hi> of <hi>Righteousness</hi> generated <hi>in them,</hi> I can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not but <hi>love</hi> them both for the sake of the <hi>Workman</hi> that <hi>made them,</hi> and the <hi>Work</hi> of his <hi>Holiness</hi> that is wrought <hi>in them;</hi> for though the <hi>Work</hi> is <hi>little,</hi> and but the <hi>least of Works,</hi> yet it is a <hi>Work</hi> of the GOD that <hi>cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ated the glories of the He<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap>ns,</hi> and though the <hi>Seed</hi> be <hi>little,</hi> yet it is the <hi>Seed</hi> of <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap>e of the great King, and though the <hi>Seed</hi> be but in the <hi>Wombs</hi> of your <hi>Mindes</hi> as yet not <hi>quickned,</hi> or if <hi>quickned</hi> yet <hi>not born,</hi> or if <hi>born</hi> yet but a <hi>Babe</hi> and <hi>poor Infant,</hi> yet in its <hi>degree, measure, stature</hi> or <hi>growth,</hi> it is in the <hi>least,</hi> as <hi>really</hi> of <hi>God,</hi> as is the <hi>greatest,</hi> that is nourished by his <hi>Omnipotent strength</hi>
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:98357:7"/> unto the <hi>fortitude</hi> of a mighty <hi>Giant,</hi> and being <hi>weak</hi> there is a greater need of the <hi>help</hi> of <hi>Love,</hi> in the care of <hi>Loves bowels;</hi> and therefore let him that thinks he is the <hi>strongest</hi> in his Judgement, Knowledge, or Opinion, shew his <hi>strength,</hi> and approve it, in every eye to be of <hi>God,</hi> by exercising it in the <hi>strength</hi> of the <hi>Love</hi> of <hi>God,</hi> to the gathering all into the same <hi>power</hi> and <hi>strength</hi> of the <hi>Love</hi> and <hi>Life of God:</hi> which I declare unto you all is <hi>my Life,</hi> which stands in the nature of the <hi>Love</hi> of God, and not onely in an audible denomination or name; for my <hi>Love</hi> is to all your <hi>persons</hi> and <hi>souls,</hi> and the <hi>Seed of God in your souls,</hi> and have no <hi>enmity</hi> against our <hi>enemies,</hi> but against the seed of <hi>enmity</hi> in all <hi>enemies</hi> or others, upon the face of the earth. And my <hi>unity</hi> is with the <hi>Seed of God in you all,</hi> under what <hi>terms</hi> of <hi>Names, descriptions,</hi> or <hi>denominations</hi> soever, which seek the <hi>God</hi> of <hi>Jacob,</hi> in the <hi>uprightness</hi> and <hi>sincerity</hi> of your <hi>hearts.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>I speak as one that seeth the <hi>end</hi> of all <hi>distinctions</hi> and <hi>separations</hi> by <hi>Names,</hi> and such like <hi>termes</hi> and <hi>denomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nations,</hi> knowing, that by the Spirit, the <hi>true separati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on</hi> is made from the <hi>Unrighteous</hi> in his <hi>Unrighteousness,</hi> and an <hi>Unity</hi> engaged with the <hi>Weak</hi> (that are crying to be delivered from all Unrighteousness) in the Pangs of their <hi>sincere-heartedness,</hi> and in the <hi>Spirit</hi> of <hi>Uniting</hi> in the <hi>holy Nature,</hi> and <hi>separation</hi> from the <hi>un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>righteous Nature.</hi> I am even constrained <hi>for loves sake</hi> to assert this, that though I my self (in and under the Profession and Participation of the Power and Virtue of God) am <hi>charactered</hi> forth by a <hi>Name</hi> or <hi>Denomina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, distinct</hi> from other <hi>desciphering Terms</hi> or <hi>Appella<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions,</hi> known by the Name of <hi>Quaker;</hi> yet known be it unto you, that there are of the People called <hi>Seekers,
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:98357:7"/> Baptists, Independents,</hi> and <hi>others</hi> (whose <hi>Conversations</hi> become the <hi>Profession</hi> of what <hi>they own,</hi> and <hi>witness</hi> (to be of God) in <hi>themselves</hi>) whom I <hi>as truly own,</hi> and with whom I have <hi>more Unity,</hi> than with divers which are <hi>called</hi> by the Name <hi>of Quakers,</hi> whose <hi>Name</hi> have not changed them from the <hi>Nature</hi> of the <hi>Enmity</hi> which works against the heavenly Spirit of <hi>Unity,</hi> and Power of the Love of God. So it is to be understood, that the <hi>Love</hi> and <hi>Unity</hi> that I seek among all (and none other than the <hi>upright sincere-hearted to God</hi>) stands in none other than the measure of the Spirit and Grace of God, as it is given unto, and manifested <hi>in us all,</hi> which (as it's improved in our Hearts) will keep our Minds up <hi>to God,</hi> and stay our Souls <hi>in himself,</hi> and fashion and frame us into a <hi>gratious Life,</hi> well-pleasing unto himself; which is the Principle to which I stoop (in all in whom it is truly arisen and sprung up) as God hath made me in like maner, to stoop to the same as it hath plainly manifested its self in my own Soul; but to the contrary, in any I dare not bow and bend: And therefore again I say, I seek not <hi>Unity</hi> with the Spirit of <hi>Enmity,</hi> but mutual <hi>Amity</hi> with all in the Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit of Grace and Innocency; and with all (as being one that is full of <hi>Love</hi> and <hi>tenderness</hi> to all) that are <hi>labouring</hi> and <hi>travelling</hi> in <hi>Cryes</hi> and in <hi>Weaknesses,</hi> to be <hi>intirely joyned to God</hi> in the Spirit, that in the end, not any thing (of all the <hi>Heaps, Hills</hi> and <hi>Mountains</hi> that this day <hi>stand</hi> before them) may <hi>interpose,</hi> so as to <hi>obstruct</hi> their <hi>Conjunction</hi> and <hi>Union</hi> with him.</p>
            <p>And therefore, whereas <hi>some</hi> are <hi>conscientious</hi> con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning <hi>divers Particulars,</hi> which by <hi>others</hi> (in the Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit) are known to be <hi>weaker</hi> than the Spirit, which is
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:98357:8"/> the perfect <hi>everlasting Substance,</hi> who notwithstand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, they know that it is more the Shadow than the <hi>Substance,</hi> and more the <hi>Husk</hi> than the <hi>Bread</hi> that the others feed upon; yet they in Wisdom would not have a man forsake <hi>a Rock</hi> or <hi>a Husk,</hi> whilst something of <hi>sweetness</hi> is sucked out of the <hi>Rock,</hi> or whilst the <hi>Husk</hi> is green, and some little <hi>Moisture</hi> therein, before the Soul discerns the <hi>Rock</hi> to be utterly <hi>dryed up,</hi> and the <hi>Husk</hi> utterly <hi>withered</hi> and <hi>parched,</hi> so that no more <hi>Substance</hi> can be found in them for <hi>Nourishment,</hi> whilst they know not <hi>another Virtue</hi> (or rather the <hi>Virtue</hi> out of <hi>Shadowes</hi>) that is able to <hi>minister Life</hi> unto them; seeing <hi>Faith</hi> is not gained by <hi>force,</hi> but is the free <hi>Gift</hi> of God; as on the other hand, a wise Man would not <hi>link</hi> or <hi>tye himself</hi> to <hi>that</hi> which he find<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth <hi>no virtue in,</hi> but is as a <hi>feeder</hi> of <hi>Dryness</hi> with <hi>Dryness,</hi> and <hi>Death</hi> with <hi>Death,</hi> knowing that the <hi>Glorious vir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue</hi> of <hi>Everlasting Life</hi> (which is able to raise the Soul from Death unto Life) stands <hi>near him</hi> to be received <hi>of him,</hi> but <hi>slighting it</hi> as an uncertain and <hi>insufficient thing,</hi> regards it not but <hi>loseth it.</hi> And therefore, though my charity would that all should <hi>partake</hi> of the <hi>more excellent</hi> and <hi>pretious Virtue,</hi> even the <hi>Substance</hi> of the <hi>very Life of God;</hi> yet rather than I would <hi>lose</hi> my <hi>Love</hi> towards the <hi>Seed</hi> in all, which is the <hi>stronger part,</hi> I could suffer to see the <hi>Souls</hi> of <hi>many</hi> which is the weak<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er part, feeding upon the <hi>Husk,</hi> until <hi>with feeding</hi> on (that which cannot give satisfaction to the <hi>Invisible</hi> and <hi>Immortal Soul</hi>) their Souls should <hi>hunger</hi> for the <hi>Sub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stance,</hi> and in their <hi>hunger</hi> earnestly <hi>seek it,</hi> that at last they might find it and be <hi>satisfied of it.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Moreover, to <hi>this</hi> I also <hi>annex</hi> the <hi>sentence</hi> of the
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:98357:8"/>
               <hi>Blessing</hi> of the <hi>Father,</hi> to all the <hi>pure Children</hi> of <hi>his Love</hi> and <hi>Patience,</hi> who <hi>watch</hi> that they themselves may <hi>stand</hi> to the <hi>end,</hi> and wait the <hi>Lord's time</hi> for the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in of all into the Glory of the Spirit's Power, that is already revealed, or into the Glory thereof, which is yet to be revealed.</p>
            <p>And also this to all other Peoples I can say, concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing this People that are called <hi>Quakers,</hi> taking them generally; I believe you all sincere Professors of God (in England, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>) cannot say otherwise but for <hi>Truth, Righteousness, Honesty, plain Heartedness, Sincerity, Boldness,</hi> and <hi>Courage</hi> in the Lamb's <hi>spiritual Battles,</hi> there is not the like of them in <hi>pious heavenly Life,</hi> and <hi>exam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple</hi> in <hi>Persecutions, Sufferings,</hi> and <hi>all Conditions</hi> upon the face of the Earth; and therefore, why should they not be <hi>Objects</hi> of <hi>Love</hi> in your <hi>Eyes</hi> and <hi>Hearts,</hi> seeing also (as unto God, so likewise) <hi>their Love</hi> abounds <hi>to you-wards?</hi>
            </p>
            <p>All which <hi>Considerations</hi> may <hi>engage</hi> a nearer <hi>Unity,</hi> and <hi>a</hi> dearer <hi>Amity</hi> in <hi>this day,</hi> than hath in all <hi>former dayes</hi> been <hi>felt</hi> and <hi>discerned</hi> in all our Hearts <hi>one</hi> tow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ards another; The issue whereof, I leave to the mover of the Work, being perswaded, that if yet we all <hi>run not together,</hi> he will suffer the <hi>Beasts of Prey,</hi> the <hi>Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rits of Darkness,</hi> and <hi>Devilishness,</hi> to drive us <hi>faster</hi> than <hi>ever.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>But be it what it will be, I rest and abide in the love of God,
<signed>to all that are sincere hearted to God<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards, a true and faithful Friend; J. P.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="postscript">
            <pb n="16" facs="tcp:98357:9"/>
            <head>Postscript.</head>
            <p>
               <hi>IN</hi> all the foregoing <hi>Epistle</hi> (I declare) my Intent is not to <hi>establish</hi> any in that which the Lord would they should <hi>be drawn from,</hi> but that in his season, all <hi>may be more drawn into himself</hi> in the <hi>Spirit,</hi> out of the Forms of this World which pass away; Nor is my purpose an <hi>op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>posing</hi> (but rather a <hi>justifying</hi> of that which any of the Servants of God sought (in himself) <hi>to build</hi> among you; nor to <hi>throw down</hi> that which he himself in the spirit hath <hi>built</hi> in or among you; as on the other hand, I stand not to <hi>justifie</hi> the Infirmities, or <hi>uphold</hi> the Selfishness of any which have <hi>done</hi> or <hi>wrought</hi> the thing which the Hand of God in or through them hath not <hi>wrought,</hi> but have rather <hi>wrought</hi> the Workes of their own <hi>Hands,</hi> which the Soul of the Lord <hi>hath no pleasure in;</hi> But the thing which I <hi>seek</hi> is, that all Flesh may be <hi>humbled</hi> in the Dust, before the Lord God, and <hi>he</hi> in <hi>his Spirit</hi> of <hi>Life</hi> and <hi>Glory, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>alted</hi> in and over all in <hi>Judgment, Truth,</hi> and <hi>Righte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ousness,</hi> for <hi>ever</hi> and <hi>ever;</hi> and in this for all to <hi>come</hi> in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to, and <hi>hold Unity</hi> and <hi>Amity</hi> to the end.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>J. P.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>